<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>INFINI Console</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on INFINI Console</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Platform Overview</title><link>/docs/reference/platform/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/platform/overview/</guid><description>Platform Overview # Introduction # You can view the main indicators at these levels(cluster, node, indice and host) to understand the operation status.
Cluster # Node # Indice # Host # Host data comes from INFINI Agent reporting and node discovery of elasticsearch.
Discover Host # Click the button &amp;ldquo;Discover Host&amp;rdquo; on the right side of the host list，then click the button &amp;ldquo;add hosts&amp;rdquo; to add the host to the host list after checking.</description></item><item><title>Installation</title><link>/docs/getting-started/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/getting-started/install/</guid><description>Installing the Console # INFINI Console supports mainstream operating systems and platforms, the package is small, without any additional external dependencies, it should be very fast to install :)
Preparation before Installation # Prepare an Elasticsearch cluster that can store data. The required version is 7.3 or above, which is used for INFINI Console to store related data.
Downloading # Select a package for downloading in the following URL based on your operating system and platform:</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>/docs/reference/agent/manage/manage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/agent/manage/manage/</guid><description>Agent Overview # Overview # Agent Manage includes functions such as auditing, viewing status, tasks setting, etc. It is the place to manage Agent.
Add Agent # Agent &amp;gt; Instance click Discover Agent。 Select the correct Agent and click Add Agents. Delete Agent # Agent &amp;gt; Instance，click Delete, delete after confirmation。 Task Settings # Agent &amp;gt; Instance，click Task Setting，configure the task, then click Save</description></item><item><title>Cluster Monitoring</title><link>/docs/reference/platform/monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/platform/monitoring/</guid><description>Cluster Monitoring # Introduction # When the monitoring of the registered cluster is enabled, the INFINI Console will periodically collect data from the target cluster according to the corresponding configuration. Including some metrics at the cluster, node, and index level. These metrics can then be observed in cluster monitoring to understand the running status of the target cluster.
List of Elasticsearch API permissions required for monitoring # _cluster/health，_cluster/stats，_cat/shards, /_nodes/&amp;lt;node_id&amp;gt;/stats _cat/indices, _stats, _cluster/state, _nodes, _alias, _cluster/settings</description></item><item><title>Alerting Center</title><link>/docs/reference/alerting/message/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/alerting/message/</guid><description>Alerting center # Introduction # By default, the message center displays the alerting events that are currently occurring in the system, which is convenient for administrators to quickly preview the execution status of the system.
Message list # The message list aggregates all triggered alerting events. If each alerting rule repeatedly triggers multiple alerting messages, only one will be aggregated and displayed here. Click the details to see more information.</description></item><item><title>Alerting Rules</title><link>/docs/reference/alerting/rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/alerting/rule/</guid><description>Alerting Rules # Introduction # The alerting rules include the configuration of four parts: data source, metrics definition, trigger condition, and message notification
Alerting rules list # In the alerting rules list, you can query the alerting rules that have been added
New alerting rule # Click the New button in the alerting rule list to enter the new alerting rule page
Configure data source # Select a cluster (required) Select index, support input index pattern (required) Input elasticsearch query DSL query filter conditions (optional) Select time field (required) Select the statistical period (for time field aggregation, the default is one minute) Configure alerting metrics and trigger conditions # Input the rule name Add the grouped fields and group size as needed, you can add more than one for terms aggregation Select the metrics aggregation field and statistics type, you can configure more than one, when configuring more than one, you must configure a formula to calculate the final metrics Configure alerting trigger conditions Select execution check cycle Input the title of the alerting event (template, referenced by the title in the template variable, click here to learn about template syntax ) Input alerting event message (template, referenced by message in template variable, click here for template syntax ) Configure message notification # Configure notification channels, which can be reconfigured, or you can use the add button to select an already created channel as a template to quickly fill in, and support adding multiple Choose whether to enable notification upgrades as needed Select silence period (how often notification messages are sent) Configure notification sending time period Click the save button to submit Update alerting rules # Select the alerting rule to be updated in the alerting rules list and click the Edit button to enter the update alerting rules page</description></item><item><title>How to specify built-in account name and password to start INFINI Console</title><link>/docs/tutorials/start_with_specify_user/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/tutorials/start_with_specify_user/</guid><description>How to specify built-in account name and password to start INFINI Console # Prepare # Download and install the latest version of INFINI Console Enable INFINI Console Security Features INFINI Console built-in account # INFINI Console has a built-in administrator account with security turned on. Without specifying an account name and password, INFINI Console defaults to the built-in account&amp;rsquo;s username and password as admin.
Specify the account name and password to start INFINI Console # INFINI Console supports the use of environment variables to specify the account name and password to start.</description></item><item><title>Index Management</title><link>/docs/reference/data/indices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/data/indices/</guid><description>Index management # Index list # The index list includes addition, deletion, modification, and lookup operations on indexes.
New index # Input the new index name and index settings to complete the addition.
Index details # You can view the index health status, number of shards, number of documents, storage size and other details, as well as view and modify Mappings and Edit settings.</description></item><item><title>Index Settings</title><link>/docs/getting-started/ilm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/getting-started/ilm/</guid><description>Index Settings # All monitoring metrics of INFINI Console are stored in the Elasticsearch index. As time goes by, the data will increase. We can configure the life cycle of the index to adapt to our monitoring storage requirements.
Configure the Default Index Template # Then you can configure the index template of the Elasticsearch cluster, and execute the following command on the system monitoring cluster to create the index template.</description></item><item><title>Installing Agent</title><link>/docs/reference/agent/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/agent/install/</guid><description>Installing The Agent # INFINI Agent is a submodule of INFINI Console, charge of data scraping and Elasticsearch instance manage. it&amp;rsquo;s manage by INFINI Console INFINI Agent supports mainstream operating systems and platforms. The program package is small, with no extra external dependency. So, the agent can be installed very rapidly. Before You Begin # Install and keep INFINI Console running.
Download # Download the current INFINI Agent package for your platform.</description></item><item><title>Alerting Channels</title><link>/docs/reference/alerting/channel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/alerting/channel/</guid><description>Alerting Channels # Introduction # The alerting channel is used to configure the channel for sending notification messages when an alerting rule is triggered. Currently, webhook is supported.
Channes list # In the channels list, you can query the channels that have been added
New alerting channel # Click the New button on the channels list page to enter the new alerting channel page
Input channel name (required) Select channel type (currently only webhook is supported) Input the webhook address Select the method of HTTP request, the default is POST Add HTTP request headers as needed Configure the webhook request body Click the save button to submit Update channel configuration # Select the channel to be updated in the channels list and click the Edit button to enter the update channel configuration page</description></item><item><title>Alias Management</title><link>/docs/reference/data/alias/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/data/alias/</guid><description>Alias Management # Alias list # The alias list includes addition, deletion, modification, and search operations for aliases.
New alias # Alias: Input an alias name Index: Select the target index corresponding to the alias, and use (*) to bind multiple indexes. Is Write Index: specify whether the selected index is writable. If the alias only binds one index, the index is writable by default; if multiple indexes are bound by (*), it is most necessary to specify one of the indexes as writable .</description></item><item><title>How to easily create an Elasticsearch "guest" user</title><link>/docs/tutorials/create_readonly_account/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/tutorials/create_readonly_account/</guid><description>How to easily create an Elasticsearch &amp;ldquo;guest&amp;rdquo; user # Introduction # In some cases, we want to share some functions or data with customers, but do not want the data to be modified. At this point we need to create a &amp;ldquo;guest&amp;rdquo; user. This article briefly describes how to create a &amp;ldquo;guest&amp;rdquo; user using the INFINI Console.
Prepare # Download and install the latest version of INFINI Console Enable INFINI Console Security Features Creating a Role # Click System &amp;gt; Security Settings on the left menu of INFINI Console, and select the Role Tab page to enter the role management page.</description></item><item><title>How to assign different Elasticsearch cluster access permissions to different INFINI Console accounts</title><link>/docs/tutorials/role_with_different_rights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/tutorials/role_with_different_rights/</guid><description>How to assign different Elasticsearch cluster access permissions to different INFINI Console accounts # Introduction # This article will introduce the use of INFINI Console to assign two different Elasticsearch cluster management permissions to two different accounts
Prepare # Download and install the latest version of INFINI Console Enable INFINI Console Security Features Register at least two Elasticsearch clusters to the INFINI Console Creating a Role # Click System &amp;gt; Security Settings on the left menu of INFINI Console, and select the Role Tab page to enter the role management page.</description></item><item><title>How to assign Elasticsearch index-level permissions to INFINI Console accounts</title><link>/docs/tutorials/role_with_index_limit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/tutorials/role_with_index_limit/</guid><description>How to assign Elasticsearch index-level permissions to INFINI Console accounts # Introduction # This article will introduce the use of INFINI Console to limit an account to only have the management permissions of certain indexes in the Elasticsearch cluster
Prepare # Download and install the latest version of INFINI Console Enable INFINI Console Security Features Register at least two Elasticsearch clusters to the INFINI Console Creating a Role # Click System &amp;gt; Security Settings on the left menu of INFINI Console, and select the Role Tab page to enter the role management page.</description></item><item><title>Data View</title><link>/docs/reference/data/view/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/data/view/</guid><description>Data View # View list # Creating and managing data views can help you better get data from Elasticsearch.
Create data view # Step 1 Define the data view # Input a view name Matching rules: Match the corresponding index, you can also use (*) to match multiple indexes. Step 2 Configuration # Select time field as time filter for view index</description></item><item><title>Container Deployment</title><link>/docs/reference/agent/docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/agent/docker/</guid><description>Container Deployment # INFINI Agent supports container deployment.
Download Image # The images of INFINI Agent are published at the official repository of Docker. The URL is as follows: https://hub.docker.com/r/infinilabs/agent
Run the following command:
docker pull infinilabs/agent:latest Verifying the Image # After downloading the image locally, you will notice that the container image of INFINI Agent is very small, with a size less than 25 MB. So, the downloading is very fast.</description></item><item><title>Docker</title><link>/docs/getting-started/docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/getting-started/docker/</guid><description>Container Deployment # INFINI Console supports container deployment.
Downloading an Image # The images of INFINI Console are published at the official repository of Docker. The URL is as follows:
https://hub.docker.com/r/infinilabs/console
Use the following command to obtain the latest container image:
docker pull infinilabs/console:latest Verifying the Image # After downloading the image locally, you will notice that the container image of INFINI Console is very small, with a size less than 30 MB.</description></item><item><title>Role</title><link>/docs/reference/system/security/role/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/system/security/role/</guid><description>Role Management # Introduction # Role Management includes CURD operations for role. And INFINI Console has a builtin role named Administrator, it has all privileges , includes Platform and Data. The data role can help us control privileges of elasticsearch, includes elasticsearch api privileges which can be configured in the file config/permission.json of your setup path.
Create Platform Role # Input role name, role name should be unique.</description></item><item><title>User</title><link>/docs/reference/system/security/user/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/system/security/user/</guid><description>User Management # Introduction # User Management includes CURD operations and reset password for user.
Create User # User name is required, and it should be unique. Nick name, phone, email, is optional. Select one or more role. Tags is optional, it helps you group users. Search User # Input keywords and click the search button to query users.
Update User # Modify as needed, and then click the Save button to submit.</description></item><item><title>Discover</title><link>/docs/reference/data/discover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/data/discover/</guid><description>Discover # Introduction # In Discover, you can search and query the data under the index or view according to conditions such as time and fields. The data display methods include regular mode and Insight mode.
Search toolbar # Index (View) # Search Statement # Time Range # Field Filter # Save Search # Saved Search List # Insight Mode Switch # Insight Configuration # Normal Mode # Flexibly add fields to data content with multi-function charts in normal mode</description></item><item><title>Settings</title><link>/docs/reference/system/security/settings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/system/security/settings/</guid><description>Settings # Disable built-in users # When the security is turned on, start the console without specifying the user and password, the system will have a The default built-in user admin. The built-in user can be disabled after adding a new user with administrator privileges.
Can&amp;rsquo;t disable yourself using built-in user</description></item><item><title>How to Monitor Elasticsearch Cluster Health</title><link>/docs/tutorials/cluster_health_change/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/tutorials/cluster_health_change/</guid><description>How to Monitor Elasticsearch Cluster Health # Introduction # In many cases, the cluster health status of the Elasticsearch cluster will turn red for some reason. At this time, at least one primary shard in the Elasticsearch cluster is unallocated or lost. So it is necessary to monitor the health status of the Elasticsearch cluster. This article will introduce how to use the INFINI Console alerting feature to monitor the health of an Elasticsearch cluster.</description></item><item><title>How to monitor Elasticsearch cluster node disk usage</title><link>/docs/tutorials/cluster_node_disk_usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/tutorials/cluster_node_disk_usage/</guid><description>How to monitor Elasticsearch cluster node disk usage # Introduction # When the system disk usage is too high, data cannot be written into the Elasticsearch cluster, which is likely to result in data loss. Therefore, monitor the Elasticsearch cluster. Node disk usage is necessary. This article will show you how to monitor your Elasticsearch cluster using INFINI Console alerts Node disk usage.
Prepare # Download and install the latest version of INFINI Console Register Elasticsearch cluster using INFINI Console Create alerting rule # Open INFINI Console in the browser, click on the left menu &amp;ldquo;Alerting&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt; Rules to enter the alerting management page, and then click New button to enter the Create Alerting Rule page.</description></item><item><title>How to monitor slow query requests in Elasticsearch</title><link>/docs/tutorials/cluster_slow_request/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/tutorials/cluster_slow_request/</guid><description>How to monitor slow query requests in Elasticsearch # Introduction # Many times, the Elasticsearch cluster will experience peak data writing or query traffic. At this time, the Elasticsearch cluster will be under a lot of pressure. Through the monitoring and alertinging of the delay of the Elasticsearch index query. This allows us to locate which indexes are the most stressed on the Elasticsearch cluster. This article will introduce how to use the INFINI Console alerting function to monitor the slow query request index in Elasticsearch.</description></item><item><title>How to monitor the CPU usage of Elasticsearch cluster nodes</title><link>/docs/tutorials/cluster_node_cpu_usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/tutorials/cluster_node_cpu_usage/</guid><description>How to monitor the CPU usage of Elasticsearch cluster nodes # Introduction # This article will introduce how to use the INFINI Console to monitor the disk usage of Elasticsearch cluster nodes and alert them.
Prepare # Download and install the latest version of INFINI Console Register Elasticsearch cluster using INFINI Console Create alerting rule # Open INFINI Console in the browser, click Alerting &amp;gt; Rules on the left menu to enter the alerting management page, and then click the New button to enter the alerting rule creation page.</description></item><item><title>How to monitor JVM usage of Elasticsearch cluster nodes</title><link>/docs/tutorials/cluster_node_jvm_usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/tutorials/cluster_node_jvm_usage/</guid><description>How to monitor JVM usage of Elasticsearch cluster nodes # Introduction # This article will introduce how to use the INFINI Console to monitor the JVM usage of Elasticsearch cluster nodes and generate alerts.
Prepare # Download and install the latest version of INFINI Console Register Elasticsearch cluster using INFINI Console Create alerting rule # Open INFINI Console in the browser, click on the left menu &amp;ldquo;Alerting&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt; Rules to enter the alerting management page, and then click New button to enter the Create Alerting Rule page.</description></item><item><title>Template variables</title><link>/docs/reference/alerting/variables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/reference/alerting/variables/</guid><description>Template variables # Introduction # When custom alerting triggers event content, in addition to the fixed copy written by yourself, the event title and event content also support template syntax. The rendering of the text can be achieved using fields in the event.
Variables # The syntax for rendering fields is {{ .fieldname }}, and the variable fields that can be used for template content rendering are as follows:</description></item></channel></rss>